Fabio Papa – Full-Stack Web Developer

email: me@fabiopapa.dev

mobile: +1 (778) 230-5559 web: http://localhost:4000 fapapa fapapa fabio-papa-dev in

Summary

Software developer with over 15 years of experience in **full-stack** web development, with a strong focus on *Ruby on Rails* and *React*. Believes deeply in finding the simplest-possible solution, and iterating over it until an elegant, joy-eliciting solution emerges. Passionate about clean, readable code that communicates intent, *test-driven-* and *behavior-driven-design*, and clean user interfaces.

Experience

Freelance Developer, Self-Employed; Coquitlam, BC - 2004-present

- ★ Write and maintain Ruby on Rails applications for companies and individuals
- ★ Champion use of user stories with non-technical stakeholders
- ★ Spearhead initiative to go from in-house physical deployment to AWS, Digital Ocean, and other cloud providers, reducing down-time and eliminating need to hire additional technical staff
- ★ Slash deployment issues and time by integrating Docker containerization to equalize test/development/production environments
- ★ Invigorate stakeholders by turning the user stories developed with them into acceptance/system tests using Gherkin/Cucumber, which they can see failing or passing
- ★ Shorten feedback loop and development cycle by implementing only minimum viable changes and deploying immediately, resulting in greater participation and excitement in developing the software by stakeholders and all users
- ★ Implement a test-first, behavior-driven design methodology, resulting in higher willingness to make
 and increased confidence in—changes to the software

Mentor, Lighthouse Labs; Vancouver, BC — 2020-present

- ★ Assist bootcamp students with debugging, code reviews, and explanation/exploration of programming topics
- * Assess student progress and identify students needing further attention
- rovide guidance to students as they pick and flesh-out their mid-term and final projects
- ★ Nurture students who are struggling, pin-pointing any foundational problems that are keeping them from learning new concepts, and devising a plan for them to execute to get on-track
- ★ Lead mock technical interviews to allow student to practice, and to further identify any holes in knowledge

Owner/Franchisee, Mr. Pretzels; Vancouver, BC — 2016-2019

- ★ Owned and successfully managed three high-traffic locations
- ★ Implemented POS and digital signage infrastructure, allowing for remote updating of prices, synchronizing of menus across stores and effective lookup of real-time sales data
- ★ Procured a cloud-based software package to create and disseminate employee schedules, resulting

- in great reduction of under-/over-staffing and missed shifts, and increased employee satisfaction
- Reduced waste product and lost sales by writing software to be used by supervisors on location to calculate expected sales for remainder of day
- ★ Hired and managed employees, building a customer-centric culture

Procurement Specialist, Long View Systems; Vancouver, BC - 2015-2017

- ★ Earned a place on the Cisco Procurement team in addition to General Procurement team through proven attention to detail and ability to manage time well
- ★ Collaborated with Account Managers, Project Managers, Consultants, manufacturers, logistics and more to successfully win and manage multi-million dollar deals
- ★ Leveraged pricing programs, on-line technical resources and manufacturer experts to solve customers' business problems

Inside Sales Rep., Metafore Technologies; Richmond, BC - 2010-2015

- ★ Integral in landing largest account in branch history
- ★ Developed innovative solutions for managing customer just-in-time inventory
- ★ Acted as a Subject Matter Expert and Trainer for company-wide, multi-year CRM deployment (to MS Dynamics AX)
- ★ Took initiative to become an evangelist for our in-house customer-facing e-commerce solution

Skills

Languages

Ruby, JavaScript, Python, Elixir, HTML, CSS

Testing

rSpec, Cucumber, Capybara, Selenium, Watir, FactoryBot, TimeCop, Mocha, Chai, Jest, Cypress, Storybook

Frameworks, Libraries, etc.

Rails, NodeJS, React, Ajax, Axios, Express, EJS, JQuery, Bootstrap, ActiveRecord, SASS, Docker, good understanding of HTTP request/response life-cycle, REST, Web Sockets

Systems, CMS && Databases

SQL (various dialects), Git, GitFlow, Subversion, AWS, DigitalOcean, Heroku, Gem, Bundler, NPM, Yarn, Webpack, comfortable setting up domains and DNS records

Projects && Contributions

Please see my website at fabiopapa.dev

Education

Lighthouse Labs, December 2019

Diploma of Web Development

Hebrew University of Jerusalem; Coursera, March 2019

Build a Modern Computer from First Principles: From Nand to Tetris Part I

Grade achieved: 100%

Build a Modern Computer from First Principles: From Nand to Tetris Part II

Grade achieved: 96.8%